CEDRIC HELEWAUT

Lucas de Heerestraat 35, 9000 Ghent, Belgium | +32 470 82 86 00 cedrichelewaut.be | cedric_helewaut@hotmail.com | linkedin.com/in/cedrichelewaut

SUMMARY

Highly driven Computer Science Engineer with a passion for Digital Strategy and Sustainable Innovation. Experienced in Product Management, Digital Strategy, Machine Learning, and Advanced Algorithms. Strong academic background, enhanced by an exchange program in Montréal and an excellence program focused on Innovation for Society.

EXPERIENCE	
 Technical Young Graduate, Proximus Rotated through multiple roles at Belgium's leading telecom operator. 	09/2023 - Present
 AI Strategy Expert, Proximus Ada Developing strategies for scaling AI-based solutions into market-ready products. 	05/2024 - Present
 Product Manager, BICS Managed international products for transactional security and fraud prevention. Provided strategic advice on data usage and policy. 	09/2023 - 04/2024
 Computer Science Engineering Intern, Optioryx Developed AI-based solutions enhancing supply chain efficiency and sustainability. Optimized 3D-bin-packing algorithms using novel data structures. 	08/2022 - 05/2023
Computer Science Engineering Intern, InThePocket • Provided data-driven insights on team dynamics.	07/2021 - 08/2021
• Contributed to on Machine Learning projects in an agile environment.	
EDUCATION	
 M.Sc. in Computer Science Engineering, Ghent University Master's Dissertation on Detecting Immersion in Multimedia using Physiological Data and Machine Learning. Course work on Machine Learning, Information Security, Computer Systems, Distributed Systems, Networks, Multimedia, and Sustainable Computer Engineering. 	09/2021 - 06/2023
 International Exchange in Software Engineering, Polytechnique Montréal Course work on Advanced Cloud Computing and Software Quality. 	08/2022 - 12/2022
 Excellence Program in Innovation for Society, Ghent University Investigated the role of engineers in achieving UN SDGs. Identified racial bias in ML-based facial recognition systems. 	09/2021 - 06/2022
B.Sc. in Computer Science Engineering, Ghent University	09/2017 - 06/2022
SKILLS	
Languages: Dutch (Fluent), English (Fluent), French (Professional proficiency) Technical Skills: Python, Java, C++, Pandas, Excel, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, Git, AWS Non-technical Skills: Digital Strategy, Product Management, Sustainability, Public Speak	king
OTHERS	
Hobbies: running, reading, and analog photography	

2021

2018 - 2020

2016 - 2017

Competitions: Finalist of the annual Ghent University Business Game

Youth Camp monitor at Chiro Sparregalm

Youth Camp monitor at Kazou